vopium.com 2018-03-19

# Vopium Privacy Policy

Your privacy is important to Vopium, and Vopium is committed to respecting your privacy and the confidentiality of your personal data, traffic data, and communications content.

This Privacy Statement is designed to assist you in understanding how Vopium uses and safeguards the information you provide when using Vopium Software and/or Vopium Services. 

Vopium collects and processes, or has third party service providers who collect and process personal data on Vopium’s behalf, relating to you to enable Vopium in:

  1. providing the Vopium Services, in particular to convey the communications you make by means of the Vopium Software and/or the Vopium Services; 
  2. invoicing you for your use of the Vopium Services; and 
  3. carrying out marketing activities related to Vopium Services

In this Privacy Statement, the following capitalised definitions are used in the singular and plural.

**_What are Cookies: A Cookie is a small file which is placed on your computer or device when you visit a website. Cookies are essential for the functionality of most websites and help users access the content that they looking for. Cookies also monitor website performance and usage, providing information that helps improve products and services and also identify areas that may require maintenance. Cookies can remember your preferences on websites including saving your username to make log-in easier when you return._**

**_How to control the use of Cookies: You are not obliged to accept Cookies. Browsers lets you view the Cookies that you have installed and control their use. You can allow them, delete them individually or delete all. But note that most websites only function properly with Cookies, and you may experience slowing down of your browsing experience or even being blocked from content you require if you chose to delete Cookies. In order to manage your Cookies, please follow the instructions of your browser supplier._**

Communications Content: Any information that is communicated by you when utilising Vopium Software and/or Vopium Services being this calls or SMS terminated via cellular network, VoIP, 3G data, WiFi etc. or instant messages through Vopium or 3rd party providers supported through the Vopium Service;

Feedback Information: Any information that is reported to Vopium by filling in the feedback forms on the Website;

Passive Information: Information that is necessary in order to provide you with the desired functions of the Vopium Software, such as but not limited to session ID tokens, source and destination addressing information, and the version of the software you are using;

Personal Data: Any information that Vopium possesses relating to an identified or identifiable user of Vopium Software and/or Vopium Services;

Registration Information: Any information provided when voluntarily registering on the Website, including, but not limited to, username and password;

Vopium: Under this Privacy Statement, the company incorporated under the laws of Denmark: Vopium A/S Emdrupvej 28A, DK-2100 Copenhagen Ø VAT No: DK 29 52 19 80

Vopium Software: Vopium software that allows you to communicate with any telephone number in the world free or at very low cost via cellular network, VoIP, 3G data, WiFi etc., send SMS, IM and other communications supported by Vopium and back-up of mobile data. The Services may be extended or altered from time to time;

Subscriber Information: Information required in order to verify your identity and to provide you with the Vopium Services, such as but not limited to your name, billing information and email address as provided by you on the Website;

User Profile: Any information about you, the user, provided by you on the Website or through the Vopium application, that is intended to be shared with other users of Vopium Software, and/or can be searched for by other Vopium users, and/or (only with the your approval) can be added to another user’s contact list, including the user’s own contact list;

Vopium Services: The free as well as the payable Services provided by Vopium and/or Vopium’s partners, including but not limited to, termination of calls, sending of SMS, IM, back-up and other Services which may be extended or altered from time to time;

Website: The Vopium Website as found at [http://vopium.com](http://vopium.com/);

You: You, the user of the Vopium Software and the Vopium Services, also used in the form “your” where applicable. You, the user of the Vopium Software and the Vopium Services, also used in the form “your” where applicable.

  * What is Vopium and what Services are offered?
  * What information does Vopium collect?
  * How does Vopium use this information and for what purpose?
  * To whom does Vopium transfer your personal information?
  * What are “cookies” and how does Vopium use them?
  * How far does Vopium’s responsibility extend?
  * How does Vopium protect your personal information?
  * Can this Privacy Statement be modified?
  * What rights do you have and how can you contact Vopium?

1\. What is Vopium and what Services does Vopium offer?  
Vopium is a company established under the laws of Denmark. Through the Website, Vopium offers you Vopium Software such as the Vopium Services, which may be extended or altered from time to time.

2\. What information does Vopium collect?  
In order to provide the Vopium Software, Vopium gathers and processes the following information:

  * Registration Information, i.e. phone number
  * User Profile
  * Email Address

Email Address: In order to provide you with Vopium Services, Vopium shall, in addition to the abovementioned information, collect and process the following information:

  * Subscriber Information

Vopium does NOT collect any Communications Content.

3\. How does Vopium use this information and for what purpose?  
Our primary purpose in collecting information is to provide you with safe, smooth, efficient and customised services. We may use the information defined in this Privacy Statement to:

  * Provide the Services and customer support you request
  * Resolve disputes
  * Collect fees
  * Troubleshoot problems
  * Customise, measure, and improve Vopium Software, Services, and Website content and layout 
  * Inform you about targeted marketing, service updates, and promotional offers (unless you explicitly request not to receive such information)
  * Compare information for accuracy, and to verify your identity
  * Provide other Services for you as described when we collect the information
Additionally we may use your information as described below: 
  * Register Information

You need to register to use Vopium Software, and Registration Information may be needed if you want to use a particular Vopium Services.

User Profile  
Vopium stores the User Profile on a central server. You can access your User Profile from “My Vopium”. Log in at http://vopium.com in order to view, correct, complete or remove information.

Email Address  
Vopium respects the privacy of personal email accounts and stores your email addresses as securely as other Personal Data. Vopium will not send you unwanted email messages or junk mail. Your details will not be passed to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit permission. However, Vopium will use your email to send messages in case of service disruption and/or service issues. Vopium may also use email to keep you updated with news about the Vopium Software and Vopium Services. If you do not wish to receive email updates, please contact Vopium at support@vopium.com. Vopium reserves the right to use email to notify you of any eventual claims related to your use of Vopium Software and/or Vopium Services, including without limitation claims of violation of third party rights.

Subscriber Information  
Vopium asks for Subscriber Information in order to verify your identity and to provide Vopium Services. We use third party banking organisations and other providers of payment services to bill for Vopium Services and we must, therefore, supply this billing provider with the necessary billing data. Please note that your billing data is sensitive information that can be used to track your use of Vopium Services. Please be sure to keep this information safe and do not share it with others.

4\. To whom does Vopium transfer your personal information?  
Except as provided below, Vopium will not sell, rent, trade or otherwise transfer any Personal and/or Traffic Data or Communications Content to any third party without your explicit permission, unless obliged to do so under applicable laws or by order of the competent authorities.

In order to provide Vopium Services or other services you have requested, Vopium may sometimes, if necessary, share your Personal and Traffic Data with Vopium’s Affiliates (as defined in the End User License Agreement), carriers, partner services providers and/or agents, for example the providers of access numbers, distributors of Vopium Software and/or Vopium Services and/or the third party banking organisation or other providers of payment services. Vopium will always require these third parties to take appropriate organisational and technical measures to protect your Personal Data and Traffic Data and to observe the relevant legislation. Please be informed that, notwithstanding the abovementioned, in the event of a designated competent authority requesting Vopium or Vopium’s local partner responsible towards such authority, to retain and provide Personal and/or Traffic Data, or to enable access in order to intercept communications, Vopium and/or its local partner will abide to local legislation to provide all necessary assistance and information when obliged to fulfil this request.

Information collected on the Website may be stored and processed in any country in which Vopium maintains facilities. In this regard, or for purposes of sharing or disclosing data in accordance with Article 4, Vopium reserves the right to transfer information outside of your country. By using Vopium Software or Vopium Services you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. As Vopium continues to develop its business, Vopium may sell or buy subsidiaries or business units. In such transactions, as well as in the event that Vopium or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, personal information of Vopium users can likely be a transferred business asset. We reserve the right to include your Personal Information, collected as an asset, in any such transfer to a third party.

5\. How far does Vopium’s responsibility extend?  
The Website may contain links that will allow you to leave the Website and access other websites. Linked websites are not necessarily under the control of Vopium. It is possible that the privacy policies of these 3rd party websites may differ from the privacy policy of Vopium. This Privacy Statement applies solely to Personal Information that is acquired on the Website, so Vopium urges you to take care when you enter any personal information online. Vopium accepts no responsibility or liability for other websites.

6\. How does Vopium protect your personal information?  
Vopium shall take appropriate organisational and technical measures to protect the Personal Data and Traffic Data provided to it or collected by it and will not retain this data any longer than permitted in order to perform its Services or as required under relevant legislation. Your Personal and Traffic Data will only be accessed by authorised employees of Vopium and only when this is required in order to fulfil their given duties.

Vopium shall take appropriate technical measures to protect the confidentiality of the Communications Content via its Vopium Software and Vopium Services, with due observance of the applicable obligations and exceptions under the relevant legislation.

7\. Can this Privacy Statement be modified?  
Vopium reserves the right to modify the provisions of this Privacy Statement if deemed necessary. We will inform you of these changes by publishing the revised Privacy Statement at http://vopium.com/go/privacy. The revised Privacy Statement shall come into effect within thirty (30) days of such publishing. Your continued use of the Vopium Software or Vopium Services after the notice period of thirty (30) days, shall constitute your acceptance of the revised Privacy Statement. Please note that any revision requiring a change in a financial commitment from you (with the exception of changes due to currency fluctuations) will be explicitly communicated via email.

8\. What rights do you have and how can you contact Vopium?  
If you would like to exercise your right to view, correct, complete or remove your Personal Data, please contact Vopium at support@vopium.com. Vopium will fulfil your request within a reasonable period of time and upon verification of your identity, provided that the action taken by Vopium on your request does not contravene any applicable legislation.

9\. How long is your Personal Data kept by Vopium?  
Vopium will retain your information for as long as is necessary to:

  1. perform the Vopium Services;
  2. invoice you for your use of the Vopium Services and until invoicing for the Vopium Services cannot be lawfully challenged and legal proceedings may no longer be pursued;
  3. carry out Vopium marketing activities;
  4. comply with applicable legislation, regulatory requests and relevant orders from competent courts;
  5. enforce our Terms of Services; or
  6. fulfil any of the other purposes detailed in this Privacy Statement.

© Vopium A/S  
Rådhusstræde 6, 1  
DK-1466 Copenhagen K  
VAT No: DK 29 52 19 80  
Email: [support@vopium.com](mailto:%20support@vopium.com)

Last revised: December 31st 2014
